<resources>
    <!-- Title for the application. [CHAR LIMIT=12] -->
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>
    <!-- Tab names -->
    <string name="category_churches">Churches</string>
    <string name="category_historical">History</string>
    <string name="category_statues">Statues</string>
    <string name="category_museums">Museums</string>
    <string name="city">City :</string>
    <string name="address">Address :</string>
    <string name="description">Description :</string>
    <!-- City -->
    <string name="location">Constanta</string>
    <!-- Churches -->
    <string name="churchesName_1">The Carol I Mosque</string>
    <string name="churchesAddress_1">Str.Crangului Nr.1</string>
    <string name="churchesDescription_1">The mosque was built between 1910-1913, on the site of
        a former glaze, Mahmudia (from 1822-1825), at the initiative of King Carol I and the
        money of the Roman state. The project belongs to the architect Victor Gh.Stefanescu,
        the way of realization being by Gogu Constantinescu, who came especially from London for
        this construction. The actual construction of the contractor belongs to Ion Neculcea.
        The architect was decorated on this occasion by the representative of Sultan Abdul
        Hamid II, Medgidie. It is built in Arabic-Byzantine style, with Romanian architectural
        motifs. From the old mosque, the Moorish minaret was still preserved. The mosque
        consists of two parts: an inner courtyard with two wings where believers can shelter
        and wash their feet before they start praying. The total area is 450 square meters,
        the height of the 25 m dome with a diameter of 8 m and the minaret height of 37 m.
        The building is made of stone and brick, except the dome and the minaret that are
        reinforced concrete. The main portal is made of Dobrogea stone and the black marble
        door with bronze inlays. The inner columns are marble of Campulung (Mateias).
        The domes and the minaret will be covered with verses from the Quran on a gold
        background, and the rest of the walls are covered in yellow and green tiles.</string>
    <string name="churchesName_2">Orthodox Cathedral of the Holy Apostles Peter and Paul</string>
    <string name="churchesAddress_2">Str.Arhiepiscopiei Nr.25</string>
    <string name="churchesDescription_2">The architects who worked in stages and with different
        weight at the Cathedral project are: Al.Savulescu, (abandoned plan), Al.Orascu and Carol
        Benes. The construction works according to the plan and instructions given by the
        architect engineer Carol Benes. The foundation stone at the foundation of the edifice
        was laid on September 4, 1883, but the works continued during 1884-1885, making a
        provisional reception on September 25, 1885. Sanctification of the church dedicated to
        the Apostles Peter and Paul takes place only on May 22 1895. The decoration of the
        interior is done by the architect Ion Mincu (for furniture - the catapetasm, the
        emperors candles, the candles, the side, etc.), and the painter George Demetrescu
        Mirea for the fresco. Only the portraits of King Carol I and Queen Elizabeth are made
        by the painter Oscar Obedenaru (1866-1915). Severely damaged during the war to
        re-establish the nation, in 1922 the problem of repairs was raised. Already the
        fresco painted by Mirea was blackened due to a poor preparation of the plaster.
        He is authorized to restore the interior of the cathedral by the Ministry of
        Religious Affairs, the church painter, Gheorghe Raicu. In August 1941, the cathedral
        suffered damage to the roof, masonry and painting, but the repairs began only in 1946,
        according to the estimates of the architect Ionescu Berechet. The church reopened in
        1951, being sanctified by PF Justinian, Patriarch of the Romanian Orthodox Church and
        Bishop Chesarie. The frescoes later recovered, the reprocessing performed in the
        Neo-Soviet style by the painters Gheorghe Popescu and Niculina Dona
        Delavrancea in 1959-1961.</string>
    <!-- History -->
    <string name="historyName_1">The Genovez Lighthouse</string>
    <string name="historyAddress_1">Bdul. Elisabeta with Str.Remus Opreanu</string>
    <string name="historyDescription_1">Between 1858 and 1860, the English company Danube and
        Black Sea Railway Co: Limited, led by John Trevor Barklay, builds (probably on the site
        of a high lighted barrage by the Genoese, who traded in this area of ​​the Euxin Pontus,
        around 1300 ), Genoese Lighthouse. The construction works were led by Major Artlan Aslan,
        from the English contractor, chief vame of Constanta Harbor in 1858 and finished in 1860.
        The monument is a parallelepipedic building at the base, up to 3.5m and octagonal in rest.
        The hexagonal spiral is made of And the height of the lighthouse is 8m. At the top there is
        a metallic dome, and the internal space is cylindrical, from it a stone ladder is made.
        The frame functioned until 1913, when the new Far Carol I took over role.</string>
    <string name="historyName_2">Casino</string>
    <string name="historyAddress_2">Bd.Elisabeta, Nr.2</string>
    <string name="historyDescription_2">The casino is located in the area between 1880-1902 where
        there was a casino - a wooden building where concerts, theater and ball shows were held.
        The construction of an edifice with functions similar to the big European casinos began in
        1904. Among the entrepreneurs of the edifice are the only son of the illustrious
        storyteller, captain C.I. Creanga, confectioner and chef from Bucharest, with whom
        the Constanta City Hall had concluded on May 8, 1902, a contract Of rental. In 1903,
        Mayor Cristea Georgescu concludes a contract for the construction of a casino, with
        the architect Daniel Renard. In 1906 the fundamental stone at the casino was put in the
        variant of Petre Antonescu project. Initially, the plans were drawn by architect
        Petre Antonescu. He had designed a building whose architectural style was inspired
        by the traditions of Romanian art. After the foundations were finished, the plans
        were changed, the City Hall entrusting their modification to a French architect,
        Daniel Renard, who abandoned the principles of Romanian style in favor of the eclectic,
        Art Nouveau. The edifice ended in 1910, and in 1912 it was made the last retouching.
        Presents in the central part the patio terrace, supported on a wide porch, dominated
        by a fan-shaped stained glass. The upper part of the building is decorated with
        architectural elements of the shape of ancient ships with ram heads and seaweed garlands.
        It was restored in 1951, 1981, and in 2008 it underwent major repairs.</string>
    <!-- Museums -->
    <string name="museumsName_1">Museum of National History and Archeology Constanta</string>
    <string name="museumsAddress_1">Piata Ovidiu Nr.12</string>
    <string name="museumsDescription_1">The foundation stone at the foundation of the
        Communal Palace was laid on May 22, 1912 by the heir to the throne, Prince Ferdinand.
        After the religious service of Bishop Nifon, Prince Ferdinand signed the commemorative
        act, along with: Bishop Nifon, Constantin Pariano, Mayor Titus Cananau Other counselors.
        Initially, the projects provided for the foundation a depth of 3-4m, then 5-7m, in order
        to finally reach no less than 17m, until the builders met solid soil. The edifice is
        raised by dismantling the Neptun and Thetis streets on the old access road to the port.
        The works are stopped due to the ever-expanded costs in 1913, resumed in the summer of
        1914 and stopped again, due to the First World War, for a while. Between 1919 and 1921
        the works of the contractor, Mr. C.M. Vasilescu, after the projects of the
        Victor Stefanescuarchive ended, and on July 17, 1921, the communal palace was
        inaugurated, in two successive numbers of the Farul newspaper, by the famous I.N.Duployen
        and I.N.Roman. At the initiative of Ion Theodorescu Sion, it is proposed to paint the
        reception hall of the Communal Palace, but the fresco is performed much later, in
        the years 1966 - 1968, in an unusual vision by the painters Niculina Dona Delavrancea
        and Gheorghe Popescu. The massive and imposing construction is part of the series of
        public edifices built in Neo-Romanian style: the rhythm of columns, richly decorated at
        the base and the capite, which sustains an arcade with the all-circular opening, strongly
        underlined by strips with decoration. The entrance and the two more advanced side windows
        have stone frames. The rigorous orizontality of the building is underlined
        by a massive brick block.</string>
    <string name="museumsName_2">The Ion Jalea Sculpture Museum</string>
    <string name="museumsAddress_2">Str. Arhiepiscopiei Nr. 26</string>
    <string name="museumsDescription_2">Because it is a museum dedicated to the great sculptor
        Ion Jalea, who made his works with one hand. Museum sculpture Ion Jalea to be in Utah,
        near the cathedral St. Peter and Paul is housed in a building which bears the imprint
        architectural style Brancoveanu. The building was built at the beginning of the sec.
        nineteenth century, the work of architect Victor Stephănescu, who designed the
        National Museum of Geology in Bucharest, National Military Club in Bucharest,
        Casino Mamaia Carol I Mosque. The museum was founded in 1868 following the donation
        of his works by the artist, numbered 108. Subsequently, Heritage Museum was enriched
        after 1968, following the donation made by the artists family, leading to over 200
        works. His works are sculptures, statues, busts, reliefs, drawings and sketches,
        and evoke themes of folklore, mythology and war. The ground floor and the floor of
        the museum present the artists original works as well as the mock-ups. In the
        basement of the museum there is a stately statue depicting Queen Elizabeth. And at
        the Art Museum of Constanta, which is subordinated to the Museum of sculpture Ion Jalea
        exposed some of the artists work.</string>
    <!-- Statues -->
    <string name="statuesName_1">Bust of Mihai Eminescu</string>
    <string name="statuesAddress_1">Cazino Cliff, Genovez Lighthouse area</string>
    <string name="statuesDescription_1">Year: 1932 (1934 unveiled) Artist: Oscar Han
        (3 Dec 1981 - 14 Feb 1976) Status: There is the same place. Under the bust of
        Eminescu we see a mousse. Many think its Veronica Micle, but its actually
        Caliope. In Greek mythology, it was the muse of Music, Song, Dance and Eloquence.
        In the classical age, it is considered to be the muse of Epic Poetry.</string>
    <string name="statuesName_2">The Archer</string>
    <string name="statuesAddress_2">In front of the Ion Jalea Museum</string>
    <string name="statuesDescription_2">Year: 1926 (MINAC says 1961 - probably the location)
        Artist: Ion Jalea (19 May 1887 - 7 Nov 1983) Located in front of the Ion Jalea Museum
        Status: There is a museum. Until recently, he was in the casino park and then
        moved to the Ion Jalea Museum.</string>
</resources>
